# **HELEN OUYANG**

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I simply love the process of building digital experiences. Before becoming a Full Stack Developer, I built mobile and web user experiences as a Product Manager for 3+ years. My interest in technology and desire to get more hands on led me to learn programming. I'm also naturally curious, a fast learner, and I'm always pushing myself to learn more and do more: from mastering banana bread, to rock climbing outdoors, to learning to build beautiful websites with clean maintainable code.

## **Projects**

#### **Keyboard Warriors**

- Team Project | Demo: http://bit.ly/3mV26j7
- Developed a full stack speed typing game built on React, Express, and PostgreSQL. Features a persistent leader board. 990+ games played to date.

#### **DispatchMe**

- Individual Project | Demo: http://bit.ly/2YQANNz
- Developed a dispatch web app built on React, Bootstrap, and Google Maps API. Allows a dispatcher to create delivery tasks and then an algorithm generates an optimized route for a driver.

#### **Quiz and Tell**

- Team Project | Demo: http://bit.ly/3o2YKvS
- Developed a full stack web app built using JQuery, EJS, and Bootstrap for front-end and Express and PostgreSQL on the back-end. Allows users to create, share, and complete Buzzfeed-like trivia and personality quizzes.

## **Work Experience**

## **Product Manager & Scrum Master**

Optimity Inc | May 2019 - April 2020

- Increased completion rate from 55% to 82% by conducted user research into user onboarding experience.
- Managed scheduling and prioritization of deliverables for the launch of our first major US client.
- Established mobile analytics and user research processes.

#### **Product Manager**

Virgin Mobile | July 2016 - July 2018

- Managed roadmap and delivery of the Virgin My Benefits reward app
- Increased offers viewed by 48% and offers redeemed per user by 15% through a UI redesign that improved offer discovery.

#### **Project Manager**

Bell Canada | June 2014 - June 2016

 Managed special projects across various departments including Operations, Customer Experience, Sales, and Marketing as part of Bell's Graduate Leadership Rotation Program.

#### **Contact**

(416) 528-6907 ouyang.helen@gmail.com helenouyang.me github.com/helenohyeah linkedin.com/in/helenouyang

## **Education**

Full Stack Web Development Lighthouse Labs (2020)

**B. A. International Relations** University of Toronto (2009-2014)

## **Skills**

Agile and Scrum Project Planning Communication Leadership

## **Technical Skills**

#### Languages

JavaScript Ruby HTML CSS/SCSS SQL

#### Frameworks & Libraries

React Express JQuery Ruby on Rails Bootstrap

#### Misc

Git Mocha Chai Jest